Guide to the Human Rights Watch Records: Helsinki Watch,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Cathy Fitzpatrick Files, 1968-1993
  - Subseries III.2: Country Files
    - USSR
      - Peace
        - Issues, 1980-1985, (3 Folders) (Box 37, Folder 8-10)
        - Issues, 1986-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 38, Folder 1-2)
      - Peace Movements: Canada: Articles by Sommer, Frank D., MD:, 1981-1986 (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Peace Rights: West, 1983-1985 (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - PEACE WORK (magazine), 1988-1989 (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - Pentecostals, 1978-1988 (Box 38, Folder 6)
      - Perugia (Soviet delegations to the Third European Convention for Nuclear Disarmament), 1984 (Box 38, Folder 7)
      - Pipeline: Forced labor
        - General, 1982-1987, (2 Folders) (Box 38, Folder 8-9)
        - Forced Labor in the USSR: Preliminary Report to Congress, 1982 (Box 38, Folder 10)
      - Political Prisoners
        - General, 1984-1989, (4 Folders) (Box 39, Folder 1-4)
        - Lists
          - General, 1987-1987 (Box 39, Folder 5)
          - Helsinki Watch Report, 1987-1988 (Box 39, Folder 6)
          - Helsinki Watch Report (original), 1988 (Box 40, Folder 1)
          - List of Political Prisoners in the USSR (publication), 1986 (Box 40, Folder 2)
      - Popov, Oleg, 1982 (Box 40, Folder 3)
      - Pravda Project, 1975-1983 (Box 40, Folder 4)
      - Press
        - General, 1981-1988, (4 Folders) (Box 40, Folder 5-8)
        - Afghanistan, 1983-1988 (Box 40, Folder 9)
        - Club Glasnost, 1987-1988 (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Prisoner Exchanges
        - General, 1985-1986 (Box 41, Folder 2)
        - The Five Dissidents, 1979 (Box 41, Folder 3)
      - Prisoner Releases, 1987 (Box 41, Folder 4)
      - Prisoner Psychiatric Abuse: General, 1983-1986 (Box 41, Folder 5)
      - Prisoners: Special Concerns, 1982-1988 (Box 41, Folder 6)
      - Prisons
        - General, 1978-1988, (2 Folders) (Box 41, Folder 7-8)
        - Extra-Legal and Psychological Abuse, 1985-1986 (Box 41, Folder 9)
      - Problems of Eastern Europe
        - General, 1983-1986 (Box 41, Folder 10)
        - Financial, 1984-1985 (Box 42, Folder 1)
        - Certificate of Incorporation and table of contents, 1981-1984 (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Psychiatric Abuse
        - General, 1975-1989, (4 Folders) (Box 42, Folder 3-6)
        - Commission, 1979-1983 (Box 42, Folder 7)
        - Commission, 1984-1988 (Box 43, Folder 1)
        - Defense, 1977-1988 (Box 43, Folder 2)
        - Report of the U.S. Delegation to Assess Recent Changes in Soviet Psychiatry, 1989 (Box 43, Folder 3)
      - Public (Human Rights) Commission, 1987-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 43, Folder 4-5)
      - Public Opinion and Polls, 1982-1988 (Box 43, Folder 6)
      - Radio Free Europe and Radio Liberty, 1983-1988, (2 Folders) (Box 44, Folder 1-2)
      - Radzinsky, Oleg and Shatravka, Aleksandr, 1982-1985 (Box 44, Folder 3)
      - Ranchers for Peace, 1982-1983 (Box 44, Folder 4)
      - Referendums: Nos. 1-15, 1987-1988, (2 Folders) (Box 44, Folder 5-6)
      - Referendums: Nos. 22-31, 1988-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 45, Folder 1-2)
      - Religion
        - Religion in Communist Dominated Areas (journal), 1978-1990, (4 Folders) (Box 45, Folder 3-6)
        - Religion in Communist Lands (publication), 1990 (Box 45, Folder 7)
        - Intolerance, 1986-1988 (Box 45, Folder 8)
        - Novosti Press Agency Monthly Bulletin, 1987 (Box 45, Folder 9)
        - Millennium of Christianity, 1988 (Box 45, Folder 10)
      - Religious Believers: Defense and Briefing, 1987-1988 (Box 45, Folder 11)
      - Religious Issues, 1977-1988 (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Religious Liberty
        - General, 1977-1990, (7 Folders) (Box 46, Folder 2-8)
        - Chronicle of the Catholic Church in Lithuania, 1985-1986 (Box 47, Folder 1)
        - Keston College
        - General, 1980-1988 (Box 47, Folder 2)
        - News releases, 1990-1991 (Box 47, Folder 3)
        - Testimony--Senate Committee on Foreign Relations, 1984 (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Religious Persecution: Testimony of Cathy Fitzpatrick before the Sub-Committee on Human Rights, 1986 (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - Resistance International
        - General, 1983-1987, (2 Folders) (Box 47, Folder 6-7)
        - Press book, 1983-1984 (Box 47, Folder 8)
        - A Proposed Helsinki, 1984 (Box 47, Folder 9)
      - Returnees (émigrés who return to USSR), 1986-1987 (Box 47, Folder 10)
      - Revolution of 1917, 1985 (Box 47, Folder 11)
      - Rickert, Sheri, Censorship in the USSR, 1986 (Box 47, Folder 12)
      - Right to Emigrate from the USSR Committee, undated (Box 47, Folder 13)
      - Roginsky, Arseny B., 1981-1982 (Box 47, Folder 14)
      - Rosenthal Article: “Forgotten Prisoners”: Correspondence, 1987 (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Russian Nationalism, 1979-1985 (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - Russian Social Fund, 1979-1987 (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - Sakharov, Andrei
        - General, 1979-1984 April, (6 Folders) (Box 48, Folder 4-9)
        - General, 1984 May-1986 February, (8 Folders) (Box 49, Folder 1-8)
        - General, 1986 March-1988 April (Box 50, Folder 1-5)
        - Fifth International Hearing, 1984-1985 (Box 50, Folder 6)
        - Hunger Strike, 1981 (Box 51, Folder 1)
        - Madrid Conference, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 2)
        - Sakharov Watch, 1985-1986 (Box 51, Folder 3)
        - Samizdat
          - Bulletin, 1987-1988 (Box 51, Folder 4)
          - Examples, 1971-1987 (Box 51, Folder 5)
      - SANE and Freeze (peace group), 1988 (Box 51, Folder 6)
      - Schultz, George (thank you letter for meeting), 1987 (Box 51, Folder 7)
      - Scientists
        - General, 1979-1988 (Box 51, Folder 8-10)
        - Report of the ACM Committee on Scientific Freedom and Human Rights (Draft:Computer Scientists whose Scientific Freedom and Human Rights have been Violated ), 1982 (Box 51, Folder 11)
      - Secrecy, 1988 (Box 51, Folder 12)
      - Seytmuratova, Ayshe: Crimean Tatars, 1978-1986 (Box 51, Folder 13)
      - Shcharansky, Anatoly B., 1979-1988 (Box 52, Folder 1-3)
      - Shatravka Family, 1986-1988 (Box 52, Folder 4)
      - Skilen, Daphne--correspondence, 1983-1987 (Box 52, Folder 5)
      - Slavic Gospel Association Newsletter, 1987 (Box 52, Folder 6)
      - Slepak, Vladimir, 1978-1987 (Box 52, Folder 7)
      - SMOT (Free Inter-Professional Association of Workers), 1987-1988 (Box 52, Folder 8)
      - Social and Economic Rights, 1979-1988, (2 Folders) (Box 52, Folder 9-10)
      - Socialists Clubs, 1983-1987 (Box 52, Folder 11)
      - Solovyev, Oleg, Kaleidoscope, 1979 (Box 52, Folder 12)
      - Solzhenitsyn, Alexander, 1975-1988 (Box 52, Folder 13)
      - SOS (Campaign for Sakharov, Orlov and Shcharansky), 1983-1984 (Box 53, Folder 1)
      - Soviet Jewry
        - General, 1979-1986, (5 Folders) (Box 53, Folder 2-6)
        - General, 1987-1988, (3 Folders) (Box 54, Folder 1-3)
        - Coalition to Free Soviet Jews: Info. Package, 1988 (Box 54, Folder 4)
        - Emigration: HIAS Annual Report, 1979 (Box 54, Folder 5)
        - Magazines and newsletters (A-P), 1981-1988, (4 Folders) (Box 54, Folder 6-9)
        - Magazines and newsletters (R-Z), 1983-1988 (Box 55, Folder 1)
      - Sovietology, 1980-1990, (3 Folders) (Box 55, Folder 2-4)
      - Soviet Peace Committee, 1982-1988, (4 Folders) (Box 55, Folder 5-8)
      - SPAS: (Swedish Peace and Arbitration Society), 1987 (Box 55, Folder 9)
      - Sports, 1986 (Box 55, Folder 10)
      - Starr, S. Frederick--Articles, 1987-1988 (Box 55, Folder 11)
      - Summits, 1985-1988, (2 Folders) (Box 56, Folder 1-2)
      - Sysoyev, Vyacheslav (cartoonist), 1980-1984 (Box 56, Folder 3)
      - Testing--Nuclear, 1985-1987 (Box 56, Folder 4)
      - Thatcher, Margaret--Trip to Moscow, 1987 (Box 56, Folder 5)
      - Timofeyev, Lev
        - General, 1985-1989 (Box 56, Folder 6)
        - Articles, Proposals, 1985-1993 (Box 56, Folder 7)
        - Biographical Data, 1991-1991 (Box 56, Folder 8)
        - The Last Hope for Survival: Reflections on the Condition of Soviet Reality, 1988 (Box 56, Folder 9)
        - Visit--United States, 1989 (Box 57, Folder 1)
      - Trade, 1982-1988 (Box 57, Folder 2)
      - Trips
        - General, 1979-1988, (5 Folders) (Box 57, Folder 3-7)
        - Briefings, 1983-1988 (Box 58, Folder 1)
      - UK Trustbuilders (Peace group), 1985 (Box 58, Folder 2)
      - Ukraine
        - General, 1983-1989 (Box 58, Folder 3)
        - Dragan, Anthony, Vinnytsia: A Forgotten Holocaust, 1986 (Box 58, Folder 4)
      - Ukrainian Helsinki Group
        - General, 1975-1988 (Box 58, Folder 5)
        - Herald of Repression in Ukraine, 1981 (Box 58, Folder 6)
        - The Persecution of the Ukrainian Helsinki Group, 1980 (Box 58, Folder 7)
      - Ukrainian Newspapers
        - Smoloskyp, 1981-1986, (2 Folders) (Box 58, Folder 8-9)
        - Ukrainian Weekly, 1986-1987 (Box 58, Folder 10)
      - Ukrainian Peace Committee, 1986-1987 (Box 59, Folder 1)
      - Ukrainian Peace Group, 1983-1988 (Box 59, Folder 2)
      - Ukrainian Press Agency, 1987-1988 (Box 59, Folder 3)
      - Ukrainian Uniate (Church), 1985-1987 (Box 59, Folder 4)
      - Ukrainian World Congress of Free Ukrainians: Newsletter, 1988 (Box 59, Folder 5)
      - United Nations
        - Human Rights Committee (1985) (Box 59, Folder 6)
        - World Disarmament Resolution, 1982 (Box 59, Folder 7)
      - United States
        - Church and Clergy, 1975-1986 (Box 59, Folder 8)
        - Policy: Disarmament, 1982-1987 (Box 59, Folder 9)
        - Reagan Administration, 1983-1988, (3 Folders) (Box 59, Folder 10-12)
        - State Department
          - Administration Human Rights Critique (mainly Voice of America), 1981-1983 (Box 59, Folder 13)
          - Human Rights Bureau--General, 1979-1987 (Box 59, Folder 14)
        - Visas (Soviet Visa procedures, 1982-1988 (Box 59, Folder 15)
        - White House--Correspondence, 1988-1988 (Box 59, Folder 16)
      - USSR News Brief (publication), 1983 (Box 60, Folder 1)
      - Vatican, 1988 (Box 60, Folder 2)
      - Velikhov, Yevgeniy (Soviet academic), 1986 (Box 60, Folder 3)
      - Velikonova, Tatyana; Yakunin, Gleb; and Terlyatskas, Antanas, 1978-1986 (Box 60, Folder 4)
      - Vins, Georgi P., 1979 (Box 60, Folder 5)
      - Voinovich, Vladimir, 1978-1980 (Box 60, Folder 6)
      - Volya (Information Bulletin on Easter Europe and the USSR), 1980-1986 (Box 60, Folder 7)
      - Wallance, Greg (Report on Mission to Soviet Union and the case of Alexander and Vladimir Slepak), 1979 (Box 60, Folder 8)
      - War Registers League, 1983-1986 (Box 60, Folder 9)
      - Warsaw Pact, 1986-1987 (Box 60, Folder 10)
      - Weisblatt, Karen--Correspondence, 1983-1987, (2 Folders) (Box 60, Folder 11-12)
      - Women
        - General, 1975-1993, (4 Folders) (Box 61, Folder 1-4)
        - Chronicle of the Women’s Camp in Mordovia, USSR, 1985 (Box 61, Folder 5)
        - Mamanova, Tatyana
          - General, 1981-1983 (Box 61, Folder 6)
          - Translations (Russian feminist anthology), 1983-1984 (Box 61, Folder 7)
        - Prisoners: Document of the Moscow Group to Promote Observance of the Helsinki Accords, 1981 (Box 61, Folder 8)
        - Women in Russia (and other publications), 1979 (Box 61, Folder 9)
      - Workers
        - General, 1978-1988, (3 Folders) (Box 62, Folder 1-3)
        - Forced Labor, 1985-1988 (Box 62, Folder 4)
        - Rights, 1984-1988 (Box 62, Folder 5)
      - World Without War Council (WWWC), 1983-1988 (Box 62, Folder 6)
      - Writer & Human Rights--Amnesty International Conference, 1981 (Box 62, Folder 7)
      - Writers
        - General, 1983-1985 (Box 62, Folder 8)
        - Emigres, 1979-1988 (Box 62, Folder 9)
        - Other Artists
          - General, 1983 (Box 62, Folder 10)
          - General, 1984-1988, (6 Folders) (Box 63, Folder 1-6)
          - Russkaia Mysl, 1983-1987 (Box 63, Folder 7)
          - Writers’ Press Conference, 1982 (Box 64, Folder 1)
      - Yalta
        - Documents prepared by the Moscow Trust Group, 1982-1985 (Box 64, Folder 2)
        - News clippings, 1982-1987 (Box 64, Folder 3)
      - Youth Festival: Moscow, 1985 (Box 64, Folder 4)
      - Zunsheine, Zakhar and Tatiana (petition), 1984-1985 (Box 64, Folder 5)
      - Miscellaneous
        - General, undated (Box 64, Folder 6)
        - Ametistov, E. (article about attached decree), 1989 (Box 64, Folder 7)
        - Appeal against Crimean Tatars, undated (Box 64, Folder 8)
        - Azerbaijan, 1987-1990 (Box 64, Folder 9)
        - Boshko, A.: Appeal to the International Helsinki Federation for Human Rights--Carl von Schwartzenberg, 1987 (Box 64, Folder 10)
        - Bulletin: A Prisoners Page” Prisons and Camps in the Brezhnev-Era Samizdat, 1988-1989 (Box 64, Folder 11)
        - Case files
          - Kasianov-Burkov, 1987-1990 (Box 64, Folder 12)
          - People arrested for distributing samizdat, 1990 (Box 64, Folder 13)
        - Commission on Innovation and Information, 1990 (Box 64, Folder 14)
        - Committee for Constitutional Surveillance: Kon, Yuri, 1990 (Box 64, Folder 15)
        - Committee for Social Defense
          - Statistical data on displaced persons, 1990 (Box 64, Folder 16)
          - Zhernova-Mill, 1990 (Box 64, Folder 17)
        - Committee of Political Prisoners in the USSR: Appeals and regulations, 1989 (Box 64, Folder 18)
        - Correspondence, 1987-1990 (Box 64, Folder 19)
        - CSCE Vienna Meeting--Barats family--Galina & Vassily, 1987 (Box 64, Folder 20)
        - Dissidents
          - Grinblut, Arkadii, 1989 (Box 64, Folder 21)
          - Kizelov, Fiodor, 1987-1988 (Box 64, Folder 22)
          - List of judges involved in trials, undated (Box 64, Folder 23)
        - Driubin, Gherman: Account on being attacked, 1990 (Box 64, Folder 24)
        - First Congress of the Labor Confederation: Resolution, 1990 (Box 64, Folder 25)
        - Free Unions in the USSR (discussion on the situation of human rights), 1990 (Box 64, Folder 26)
        - Gdlian, T., Prosecutor, 1990 (Box 64, Folder 27)
        - Group for Trust Between East and West (newsletter), 1987 (Box 65, Folder 1)
        - Group: “Friendship and Dialogue”, 1987 (Box 65, Folder 2)
        - International Helsinki Federation for Human Rights Conference, Moscow, June 1990, 1990 (Box 65, Folder 3)
        - Kovalenko, Nina: Letter to U.S. Department of State, 1987 (Box 65, Folder 4)
        - Leaflet calling for demonstrations, 1990 (Box 65, Folder 5)
        - Letter to Sergei Kovalev, 1990 (Box 65, Folder 6)
        - Lyanin, A.: Abuse in army, 1990 (Box 65, Folder 7)
        - Dr. Massover’s case, 1989-1990 (Box 65, Folder 8)
        - Maximova, Galina: Appeal to CSCE to leave the USSR, 1990 (Box 65, Folder 9)
        - Medova, Natalia: Letter to Helsinki Watch, 1990 (Box 65, Folder 10)
        - Mitrokhin, Sergei, (Human rights movements in the USSR), undated (Box 65, Folder 11)
        - Moscow Bio --news releases, 1989 (Box 65, Folder 12)
        - Neyfakh, A.:Lithuanians, undated (Box 65, Folder 13)
        - Press clippings, mostly Russkaia Mys, 1986-1987 (Box 65, Folder 14)
        - Prisoners in psychiatric detention units, 1987 (Box 65, Folder 15)
        - Psychiatric abuse: Individual cases, 1986-1990 (Box 65, Folder 16)
        - Refuseniks: Lindner, Eduard, 1989 (Box 65, Folder 17)
        - Sadovsky, V.: Articles, 1989 (Box 65, Folder 18)
        - Samizdat:Day by Day, 1988 (Box 65, Folder 19)
        - Savenko, Yuri: Modern Soviet Psychiatry and Human Rights, 1989 (Box 65, Folder 20)
        - Slobodskoi, N. E., 1988-1989 (Box 65, Folder 21)
        - Sorbuchev, Sergei: Letter to Amnesty International, 1990 (Box 65, Folder 22)
        - Svetushkin, Sergei, 1987 (Box 65, Folder 23)
        - Toropov, G. A.: Letter to Larisa Bogoraz, undated (Box 65, Folder 24)
        - Volkhmentseva, G.: Freedom of association, undated (Box 65, Folder 25)
        - Wallenberg, Raoul: Resolution on his destiny and significance, 1990 (Box 65, Folder 26)
      - Yugoslavia
        - List of files: Index, undated (Box 66, Folder 1)
        - General, 1980-1989, (4 Folders) (Box 66, Folder 2-5)
        - Albanian—Ethnic--General, 1980-1989 (Box 66, Folder 6)
        - Albanian Kosovar Youth in the Free World (Newsletter), 1982-1988 (Box 66, Folder 7)
        - American Bar Association--Vladimir Mijanovic--Trial, 1984 (Box 66, Folder 8)
        - American Croatians for Human and National Rights, 1978-1987 (Box 66, Folder 9)
        - American Psychiatric Association: Correspondence, 1980 (Box 66, Folder 10)
        - Amnesty International
          - Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 66, Folder 11)
          - Reports, 1980-1989 (Box 66, Folder 12)
        - Army, 1983-1988 (Box 67, Folder 1)
        - Artukovic, Andrija, 1985-1987 (Box 67, Folder 2)
        - Associations, 1989 (Box 67, Folder 3)
        - Belgrade Six
          - Background, 1985-1986 (Box 67, Folder 4)
          - Defense, 1986 (Box 67, Folder 5)
          - Trial, 1984-1985 (Box 67, Folder 6)
        - Beloff, Nora--articles, 1984-1986 (Box 67, Folder 7)
        - Biblowit, Charles, 1985 (Box 67, Folder 8)
        - Biblowit--Paraga, 1987 (Box 67, Folder 9)
        - Bans, 1986-1987 (Box 67, Folder 10)
        - Borba (Series of articles on criminal code and prisons), 1987 (Box 67, Folder 11)
        - Bulgaria--Relations, 1983-1985 (Box 67, Folder 12)
        - Cavoski, Kosta, 1984-1987 (Box 67, Folder 13)
        - CADDY (Committee to Aid Democratic Dissidents in Yugoslavia)
          - General, 1980-1986 (Box 67, Folder 14)
          - Bulletin, 1980-1983, (2 Folders) (Box 67, Folder 15-16)
          - Bulletin, 1984-1992, (3 Folders) (Box 68, Folder 1-3)
          - Correspondence, 1979-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 68, Folder 4-5)
          - Mailing list, 1981-1984 (Box 68, Folder 6)
          - List of prisoners, 1986 (Box 68, Folder 7)
          - Press releases, statements, 1984-1987 (Box 68, Folder 8)
        - Censorship, 1980-1988 (Box 69, Folder 1)
        - Committee for the Defense of Freedom of Thought and Expression, 1982-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 69, Folder 2-3)
        - Committee for the Protection of Human Rights, 1987-1989 (Box 69, Folder 4)
        - Conscientious objectors, 1989 (Box 69, Folder 5)
        - Contacts, 1984-1988 (Box 69, Folder 6)
        - Correspondence, 1982-1987 (Box 69, Folder 7)
        - Criminal Code (excerpt), undated (Box 69, Folder 8)
        - Croatia
          - General, 1978-1986 (Box 69, Folder 9)
          - Croatian National Congress
            - General, 1979-1983 (Box 69, Folder 10)
            - CNC Report (publication), 1984-1987 (Box 69, Folder 11)
        - CSCE (Conference on Security and Cooperation in Europe), 1982-1986 (Box 69, Folder 12)
        - Dedijer, Vladimir, 1982-1984 (Box 69, Folder 13)
        - Defense of Yugoslav dissidents
          - General, 1984-1989 (Box 69, Folder 14)
          - Europe, 1984-1985 (Box 69, Folder 15)
          - United States, 1984-1987 (Box 70, Folder 1)
        - Democracy International, 1980 (Box 70, Folder 2)
        - Demonstrations, 1988 (Box 70, Folder 3)
        - Dissent, 1982-1984 (Box 70, Folder 4)
        - Djilas, Akim, 1984 (Box 70, Folder 5)
        - Djilas, Milovan, 1979-1988 (Box 70, Folder 6)
        - Djogo, Gojko, 1981-1983 (Box 70, Folder 7)
        - Economy, 1980-1988 (Box 70, Folder 8)
        - Evropska Zora (European Dawn), 1979-1980 (Box 70, Folder 9)
        - Emigres, 1982-1984 (Box 70, Folder 10)
        - Foreign relations, 1980-1986 (Box 70, Folder 11)
        - Free flow of people, 1987 (Box 70, Folder 12)
        - Freedom of association and assembly, 1988-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 70, Folder 13-14)
        - Helsinki Watch
          - Articles, 1982-1985 (Box 71, Folder 1)
          - Correspondence, 1980-1985 (Box 71, Folder 2)
            [restricted until ]
          - Missions, 1986-1989, (4 Folders) (Box 71, Folder 3-6)
          - Report:Freedom to Conform, 1981-1983 (Box 71, Folder 7)
          - Testimonies, 1991-1993 (Box 71, Folder 8)
          - Trial
            - Defense, 1984-1985 (Box 71, Folder 9)
            - Updates, 1984-1985 (Box 71, Folder 10)
        - Human rights, 1979-1987 (Box 71, Folder 11)
        - International Human Rights Law Group, 1980-1981 (Box 71, Folder 12)
        - Islam, 1983-1984 (Box 72, Folder 1)
        - Ivejaz, Pjeter, 1986 (Box 72, Folder 2)
        - Jugosloven (publication), 1980-1986 (Box 72, Folder 3)
        - Karp, Russ, 1984-1985 (Box 72, Folder 4)
        - Knjizevna Rec (magazine), 1988 (Box 72, Folder 5)
        - Kosovo
          - General, 1981-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 72, Folder 6-7)
          - Foreign Broadcast Information Service news releases, 1982-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 72, Folder 8-9)
          - Riots, 1979-1982 (Box 72, Folder 10)
        - Krsmanovic, Tomislav--Committee for the Protection of Human Rights, 1988 (Box 72, Folder 11)
        - Law, 1985-1985 (Box 73, Folder 1)
        - Lawyers Committee for International Human Rights, 1984-1985 (Box 73, Folder 2)
        - LCY (League of Communists of Yugoslavia), 1982-1989 (Box 73, Folder 3)
        - Licht, Sonja, 1989 (Box 73, Folder 4)
        - Macedonia, 1985-1986 (Box 73, Folder 5)
        - Markovic, Mihajlo, 1985 (Box 73, Folder 6)
        - Markovic, Vladimir, 1982-1986 (Box 73, Folder 7)
        - Mastnak, Tomaz, 1986 (Box 73, Folder 8)
        - Media, 1980-1986 (Box 73, Folder 9)
        - Mihajlov, Mihajlo
          - General, 1968-1989 (Box 73, Folder 10)
          - Articles, interviews, 1972-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 73, Folder 11-12)
          - Bibliography, 1961-1980 (Box 73, Folder 13)
          - Biographical data, 1979-1983 (Box 73, Folder 14)
          - Correspondence
            - General, 1979-1985 (Box 73, Folder 15)
            - Center for Appeals for Freedom (CAF), 1980-1981 (Box 74, Folder 1)
          - Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty, 1985-1987, (2 Folders) (Box 74, Folder 2-3)
        - Milisic, Miodrag, 1983 (Box 74, Folder 4)
        - Nationalities, 1985-1986 (Box 74, Folder 5)
        - Nedic, Miladin, 1986-1987 (Box 74, Folder 6)
        - Nikolic, Milan, 1984-1990 (Box 74, Folder 7)
        - Northern California's Alliance for Justice in Yugoslavia, 1987 (Box 74, Folder 8)
        - Paraga, Dobroslav
          - General, 1983-1986, 1988 (Box 74, Folder 9-10)
          - Press clippings, 1980-1989 (Box 74, Folder 11)
        - Pasic, Nicholas--The Standing Committee on Human Rights, 1987 (Box 75, Folder 1)
        - Peace, 1985-1988 (Box 75, Folder 2)
        - PEN Writers in Prison Committee, 1983-1986 (Box 75, Folder 3)
        - Political charges, arrests and sentences, 1988-1989 (Box 75, Folder 4)
        - Political prisoners, 1975-1988 (Box 75, Folder 5)
        - Popovic, Srdja, 1976-1984 (Box 75, Folder 6)
        - PRAXIS (group), 1979-1985 (Box 75, Folder 7)
        - Press
          - General, 1980-1987 (Box 75, Folder 8)
          - Correspondence, 1980-1986 (Box 75, Folder 9)
          - European, 1981-1987 (Box 75, Folder 10)
          - Post-Tito, 1979-1988 (Box 75, Folder 11)
          - Tito, 1980-1980 (Box 75, Folder 12)
          - United States, 1982-1985 (Box 75, Folder 13)
          - Yugoslav, 1983-1985 (Box 76, Folder 1)
        - Prison conditions, 1983-1986 (Box 76, Folder 2)
        - Prisoners, 1988-1989 (Box 76, Folder 3)
        - Psychiatric abuse, 1981-1988, (2 Folders) (Box 76, Folder 4-5)
        - Public prosecutor, 1984-1986 (Box 76, Folder 6)
        - Publications, 1977-1987 (Box 76, Folder 7)
        - Refugees, 1987-1988 (Box 76, Folder 8)
        - Religion
          - General, 1981-1987 (Box 76, Folder 9)
          - Religion in Communist Dominated Areas (publication), 1978-1979 (Box 76, Folder 10)
        - Robinovitz, Stuart, 1984-1985 (Box 76, Folder 11)